Finding Aid for Historic Preservation Program (Eastern Michigan University) student papers, 2010-2011
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Historic Preservation Program (Eastern Michigan University) student papers 2010-2011
Eastern Michigan University. Historic Preservation Program.
2011151 Bi 2
Student papers documenting Michigan modern architecture prepared for class on preservation research techniques taught in the Historic Preservation Program at Eastern Michigan University. Papers document buildings and residences in and around Ann Arbor.
1 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The papers (donor no. 10493 ) were received through Dr. Ted Ligibel, Eastern Michigan University Historic Preservation Program beginning in February 2011.
Periodic additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
The Historic Preservation Program, created in 1979, is a part of the Department of Geography and Geology at Eastern Michigan University. The program offers two degree choices, a Master of Science in Historic Preservation and a graduate-level Certificate in Historic Preservation. The program aims to prepare students for professions in preservation planning, historic administration, and cultural heritage interpretation in the museum, consulting and tourism fields. The program offers several concentrations for students to choose from and provides practical experience in the form of work study, internships, cooperative education and field study.
Preservation Research Techniques is a research-intensive course designed "to address preservation-oriented research problems, involving built environment and/or cultural landscape analyses as sources of applied research skills."[1] As part of the class, students prepared papers documenting the history of a variety of buildings located in the Ann Arbor area. Dr. Theodore (Ted) J. Ligibel, the Director and advisor for the Master of Science in Historic Preservation program, taught this course during the Fall 2010 and Fall 2011 terms.
----------------
1. From the course description in the archived catalog, found at http://catalog.emich.edu/preview_program.php?catoid=5&poid=3419&returnto=304; retrieved August 2011
The Student Papers series (1.0 linear foot, 2010-2011) includes papers written by graduate students in the Preservation Research Techniques course taught in the Historic Preservation Program at Eastern Michigan University. Papers are from the Fall 2010 and Fall 2011 semesters. The papers organized alphabetically by author under subseries for each semester: Documenting Michigan Modern, Preservation Research Techniques, Fall 2010 and Documenting Ann Arbor Modern, Preservation Research Techniques, Fall 2011. Each course had a theme that students incorporated into their titles, beginning with "Documenting Michigan Modern" in Fall 2010 and "Documenting Ann Arbor Modern" in Fall 2011. Both terms focused on modern structures in coordination with a larger State of Michigan initiative on documenting modernism in Michigan called "Michigan Modern."
Subjects:
Eastern Michigan University. Historic Preservation Program.; University of Michigan--Buildings.; Architecture--Michigan.; Modern movement (Architecture)--Michigan.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Buildings, structures, etc.
- Student Papers
  - Documenting Michigan Modern, Preservation Research Techniques, Fall 2010
    - Bahls, Elizabeth D. (Box 1)
      - "Documenting Michigan Modern: Ann Arbor District Library" (Box 1)
    - Bahls, Elizabeth D.
      - "Documenting Michigan Modern: Leslie and Mary White House" (Box 1)
    - Barone, Elaine
      - "Documenting Michigan Modern: David W. Osler Residence" (Box 1)
    - Barone, Elaine
      - "Documenting Michigan Modern: St. Andrew's United Church of Christ" (Box 1)
    - Berneis, Alexandra E.
      - "Documenting Michigan Modern: 374 Hilldale Drive" (Box 1)
    - Berneis, Alexandra E.
      - "Documenting Michigan Modern: Power Center for the Performing Arts" (Box 1)
    - Burdick, Eric
      - "The Dairy Queen Building" (Box 1)
    - Burdick, Eric
      - "Documenting Michigan Modern: The Wells Ira Bennet House" (Box 1)
    - Chase, Monique
      - "Documenting Michigan Modern: 300 South Ashley" (Box 1)
    - Chase, Monique
      - "Documenting Michigan Modern: 505 Burson Place" (Box 1)
    - Currier, Robin
      - "Documenting Michigan Modern: Donald J. Portman House" (Box 1)
    - Currier, Robin
      - "Documenting Michigan Modern: Letitia J. Byrd House" (Box 1)
    - de Vries, Susann
      - "Documenting Michigan Modern: Matthaei Botanical Gardens" (Box 1)
    - Freiberger, Kirsten
      - "Documenting Michigan Modern: Myer-Vitosha House" (Box 1)
    - Freiberger, Kirsten
      - "Documenting Michigan Modern: Rackham School of Graduate Studies" (Box 1)
    - Hayes, Sarah L.
      - "Documenting Michigan Modern: 447 Hilldale Drive" (Box 1)
    - Hayes, Sarah L.
      - "Documenting Michigan Modern: Harvest Mission Community Church" (Box 1)
    - Jensen, Casie
      - "Documenting Michigan Modern: Ann Arbor News Building" (Box 1)
    - Jensen, Casie
      - "Documenting Michigan Modern: Kingsbury Marzloff House" (Box 1)
    - Locker, Constance
      - "Documenting Michigan Modern: Ann Arbor Bus Depot" (Box 1)
    - Locker, Constance
      - "Documenting Michigan Modern: The Ulrich House" (Box 1)
    - Loncharich, Hannah
      - "Documenting Michigan Modern: A Lustron Home"
    - Loncharich, Hannah
      - "Documenting Michigan Modern: Longworth Showroom" (Box 1)
    - Miela, Amanda
      - "Documenting Michigan Modern: Ann Arbor City Hall" (Box 1)
    - Miela, Amanda
      - "Documenting Michigan Modern: Heatherway House" (Box 1)
    - Neitzel, Shelly
      - "Documenting Michigan Modern: Greenhills School" (Box 1)
    - Neitzel, Shelly J.
      - "Documenting Michigan Modern: 1334 Arlington Boulevard" (Box 1)
    - Newberry, Michael R.
      - "Documenting Michigan Modern: The Bentley Historical Library" (Box 1)
    - Newberry, Michael R.
      - "Documenting Michigan Modern: The Harry and Margaret Towsley Residence" (Box 1)
    - Puff, Jessica
      - "Documenting Michigan Modern: Gerald R. Ford Presidential Library" (Box 1)
    - Puff, Jessica
      - "Documenting Michigan Modern: Palmer House" (Box 1)
    - Reintjes, Amanda
      - "Documenting Michigan Modern: Burton Memorial Tower" (Box 1)
    - Siegfried, Matt
      - "Documenting Michigan Modern: 319 Brookside" (Box 1)
    - Siegfried, Matt
      - "Documenting Michigan Modern: Kluck's Drive-In Restaurant" (Box 1)
    - Ussery, Estella
      - "Documenting Michigan Modern: Metcalf House" (Box 1)
    - Ussery, Estella
      - "Documenting Michigan Modern: Washtenaw County Courthouse" (Box 1)
    - Wake, May Lyn
      - "Documenting Michigan Modern: A&W of Dexter" (Box 1)
    - Wake, May Lyn
      - "Documenting Michigan Modern: 814 W Pauline Blvd." (Box 1)
    - Wolfe, Tyler
      - "Documenting Michigan Modern: 369 Hilldale Drive" (Box 1)
    - Wolfe, Tyler
      - "Documenting Michigan Modern: University Microfilms Building" (Box 1)
    - Zhang, Xian
      - "Documenting Michigan Modern: The Campus Inn" (Box 1)
    - Zhang, Xian
      - "Documenting Michigan Modern: Huron Towers Apartments" (Box 1)
  - Documenting Ann Arbor Modern, Preservation Research Techniques, Fall 2011
    - Carpenter, Lauren E
      - "Documenting Ann Arbor Modern: 910 Barton Drive" (Box 1)
    - Constantine, Sam
      - "Documenting Ann Arbor Modern: The Hoobler-Lindenauer House, 1950" (Box 1)
    - Davis, Judith
      - "Documenting Ann Arbor Modern: 2638 Bedford Road" (Box 1)
    - Davis, Virginia
      - "Documenting Ann Arbor Modern: The Walter Sanders House" (Box 1)
    - Long, Kimberly
      - "Documenting Ann Arbor Modern: 2417 Londonderry Rd." (Box 1)
    - Musser, Gregory
      - "Documenting Ann Arbor Modern: The Terwilliger House" (Box 1)
    - Peruski, Gregory
      - "Documenting Ann Arbor Modern: 870 Belfield Circle" (Box 1)
    - Remensnyder, Katie
      - "Documenting Ann Arbor Modern: 2855 Devonshire" (Box 1)
    - Sawatzki, Gretchen
      - "1766 Glenwood Road" (Box 1)
    - Swick, Lori
      - "The Nagy House" (Box 1)
    - Wake, May Lyn
      - "A brief survey of Michigan mid-century modern homes by Home Planners Inc." (Box 1)
      - "Home Planners, Inc." (Box 1)
    - Wooten, Lindsey J.
      - "Researching Ann Arbor Modern: The Mundus Residence" (Box 1)
    - Zaremski, Lindsay
      - "Documenting Ann Arbor Modern: Mr. and Mrs. Gerald Buhrman, Jr. Residence" (Box 1)